<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers on Computational Uncertainty Lab</title>
    <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papers on Computational Uncertainty Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.138.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Early human judgment forecasts of human monkeypox, May 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2022-mpoxhj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2022-mpoxhj/</guid>
      <description>These results suggest that a human judgment forecasting platform can quickly generate probabilistic predictions for targets of public health importance</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aggregating Human Judgment Probabilistic Predictions of Coronavirus Disease 2019 Transmission, Burden, and Preventive Measures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/codi-2022-aggcovid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/codi-2022-aggcovid19/</guid>
      <description>Our work shows that aggregated human judgment forecasts for infectious agents are timely, accurate, and adaptable, and can be used as a tool to aid public health decision making during outbreaks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aggregating probabilistic predictions of the safety, efficacy, and timing of a COVID-19 vaccine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2021-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2021-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>To support public health decision making, we solicited trained forecasters and experts in vaccinology and infectious disease to provide monthly probabilistic predictions from July to September of 2020 of the efficacy, safety, timing, and delivery of a COVID-19 vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptively stacking ensembles for influenza forecasting with incomplete data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2020-adaptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2020-adaptive/</guid>
      <description>Needing no data at the beginning of an epidemic, an adaptive ensemble can quickly train and forecast an outbreak, providing a practical tool to public health officials looking for a forecast to conform to unique features of a specific season.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An expert judgment model to predict early stages of the COVID-19 outbreak in the United States</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2020-expertjudgmentcovid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2020-expertjudgmentcovid/</guid>
      <description>This work highlights the importance that an expert linear pool could play in flexibly assessing a wide array of risks early in future emerging outbreaks, especially in settings where available data cannot yet support data-driven computational modeling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aggregating predictions from experts: a scoping review of statistical methods, experiments, and applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2019-scopingreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2019-scopingreview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wires.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/wics.1514&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasts support decision making in a variety of applications. Statistical models can produce accurate forecasts given abundant training data, but when data is sparse or rapidly changing, statistical models may not be able to make accurate predictions. Expert judgmental forecasts—models that combine expert-generated predictions into a single forecast—can make predictions when training data is limited by relying on human intuition. Researchers have proposed a wide array of algorithms to combine expert predictions into a single forecast, but there is no consensus on an optimal aggregation model. This review surveyed recent literature on aggregating expert-elicited predictions. We gathered common terminology, aggregation methods, and forecasting performance metrics, and offer guidance to strengthen future work that is growing at an accelerated pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An expert judgment model to predict early stages of the COVID-19 outbreak in the United States</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2019-cox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2019-cox/</guid>
      <description>Compared to fixed effect models, random effects suffer lower bias and trade inflated type I errors for improved power. Contrasting hazard rates between trials prevent accurate estimates from both fixed and random effects models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossing points in survival analysis sensitively depend on system conditions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2018-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 13:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2018-crossing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crossing survival curves complicate how we interpret results from a clinical trial&amp;rsquo;s primary endpoint. We find the function to determine a crossing point&amp;rsquo;s location depends exponentially on individual survival curves. This exponential relationship between survival curves and the crossing point transforms small survival curve errors into large crossing point errors. In most cases, crossing points are sensitive to individual survival errors and may make accurately locating a crossing point unsuccessful. We argue more complicated analyses for mitigating crossing points should be reserved only after first exploring a crossing point&amp;rsquo;s variability, or hypothesis tests account for crossing point variability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply &amp; Supply: Efficient crowdsourcing when workers do more than answer questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2017-reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2017-reply/</guid>
      <description>By modeling question sets as networks of interrelated questions, we introduce algorithms to help curtail the growth bias by efficiently distributing workers between exploring new questions and addressing current questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we write about when we write about causality: Features of causal statements across large-scale social discourse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2016-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2016-we/</guid>
      <description>We find that causal statements have a number of significant lexical and grammatical differences compared to non-causal language</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robustness of spatial micronetworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2015-robustness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/mcandrew-2015-robustness/</guid>
      <description>Accounting for spatial effects in both construction and robustness is important for designing efficient microgrids and other network infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unusual Uses For Olive Oil</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/paper1/</guid>
      <description>This paper reviews unusual uses for olive oil throughout the Mediterranean world. Published in the Journal of Oleic Science, 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A phase II study of the PARP inhibitor ABT-888 plus temozolomide in patients with heavily pretreated, metastatic colorectal cancer.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/pishvaian-2011-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 13:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50252/computationalUncertaintyLab/complabweb/papers/pishvaian-2011-phase/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
